<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Software on Mr Plum&#39;s Linux diary</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Software on Mr Plum&#39;s Linux diary</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>To enable copy-paste between a QEMU host and guest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/qemucopypaste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/qemucopypaste/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To enable copy-paste between a QEMU host and guest, install &lt;code&gt;spice-vdagent&lt;/code&gt; (or guest tools) in the guest OS, ensure it&amp;rsquo;s running, and use the SPICE display protocol for seamless clipboard sharing, often requiring the &lt;code&gt;virtio-serial&lt;/code&gt; device and correct QEMU arguments in your setup. For Windows guests, you may also need to install VirtIO drivers, and for Linux guests, ensure the service starts correctly after X starts. &lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For Linux Guests (e.g., Ubuntu, Fedora)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Github pages, custom domains and Cloudflare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/githubpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/githubpages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The steps to getting this on &lt;a href=&#34;https://linux.plumocelot.uk&#34;&gt;https://linux.plumocelot.uk&lt;/a&gt; as oppposed to the github page url badgergeddon.github.io:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Set things up on Cloudflare with a CNAME reference linux.plumocelot.uk and point it to badgergeddon.github.io&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;DNS only&amp;rdquo; and not proxied for setting up otherwise ssl (https) will not work on github pages setup later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Go to your github pages repository and select settings&amp;gt;pages&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enter your custom domain, e.g. mine  was &amp;ldquo;linux.plumocelot.uk&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Save and hopefully your domain will resolve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You should now be able to &amp;ldquo;Enforce HTTPS&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If using a github action to build and deploy (I am using Hugo here) then you need to edit your hugo.toml file in your repo to change the base domain:&#xA;eg, mine was: baseurl = &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://linux.plumocelot.uk&#34;&gt;https://linux.plumocelot.uk&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Run &amp;ldquo;Deploy Hugo site to Pages&amp;rdquo; workflow&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Enjoy your cheapskate website on your custom domain.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Buho CMS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/buho/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/buho/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BuhoCMS is a local Content Management System for static site generators.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See BuhoCMS as a GUI for static site generators. Easily create or open a website, choose your theme and add your first posts. With BuhoCMS, adding and editing content is as easy as a few clicks. No more terminal commands, folder hunting or manual Front matter edits&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/buho.png&#34; alt=&#34;Buho&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s available on Flathub under POP OS so it just really needs Hugo installed and it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much good to go. There are a few alpha bugs - &amp;ldquo;Themes&amp;rdquo; options is not quite working so you are better off setting up the nuts and bolts of the site under Hugo and then adding your chosen theme as a submodule. Hugo do a simple tutorial &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/quick-start/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>POP!_OS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/pop_os/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/pop_os/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pop OS is a free and open-source Linux distribution based on Ubuntu and developed by the American Linux computer manufacturer System76. It features the COSMIC desktop environment; a Rust-based and Wayland-only desktop created and maintained by System76.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/posts/pop.png&#34; alt=&#34;POP!&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;POP uses COSMIC, a backronym for Computer Operating System Main Interface Components, is a free and open-source desktop environment for Linux and other Unix-like operating systems. COSMIC was originally the name of a modified version of GNOME made specifically for Pop!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
